Self-motivated software developer with a high level of experience over more than two years collaborating and working on multiple web-based projects. Passionate, hardworking coder with penchant for developing customized interfaces that factor in unique demands for accessibility, reachability and security. Organized approach to meeting multiple, concurrent deadlines. Pulls from active knowledge of current technology landscape to promote best practices in web design.

Work History

2020-01 -Current

Web Developer

Kierian Technology, Enugu, Enugu State

- Wrote lines of code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery. Also used Reactjs for my front-end and Nodejs for back-end development.
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.
- Established presentation consistency across Chrome,
 Safari, Firefox and other common browser interfaces.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.

2018-11 -2019-12

Web Developer

Naurix Technology, Enugu, Enugu State

- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Wrote lines of code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.
- Ran debugging tools such as Firebug and Chrome Inspector to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.
- Generated web hosting presence to accommodate specified needs, uploading and maintaining files on account.
- Oversaw back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.

Chika Onyema

Web Developer

Contact

Address

Yaba, Fadeyi, Lagos, 901101

Phone

07030586560

E-mail

chika.onyema01@gmail.co m

Skills

Programming

CSS

HTML

JavaScript

Website optimization

Agile Workflow

Software Best Practices

React.is

Node.js

JQuery

Express.is

MongoDb

2018-01 - Web Developer Intern

2018-11

Kierian Technology, Enugu, Enugu State

- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Supported web applications and web sites through database development.
- Studied basic project requirements with assigned technical lead and planned development strategies.
- Troubleshot and debugged code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers, and operating systems.

2017-05 -2017-12

Sales Representative

PZ Wilmar, Onitsha, Anambra

- Exceeded sales goals by at least 20% for monthly in row.
- Managed all sales plan activities, including merchandising and customer service, resulting in more sales.
- Efficiently solved complex problems that impacted management.
- Pursued minimum of twenty new leads each month.
- Utilized professional sales techniques to persuasively communicate with clients.

2016-05 -2017-04

Teacher

National Youth Service Corps Service, Nawfia, Anambra State

- Supported student teachers by mentoring on classroom management, lesson planning and activity organization.
- Kept students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.
- Reviewed curriculum and devised alternate approaches to presenting lessons to increase student understanding.
- Supervised learning groups of students in classroom stations including Government which I taught them.

Education

Languages

Igbo language

English language

2018-02 - Msc: Insurance And Risk Management

Current	Enugu State University Of Science And Technology - Enugu Currently concluding my desertification for defence.
2011-12 - 2015-08	 Bsc: Insurance And Risk Management Enugu State University Of Science And Technology - Enugu Graduated with 3.96 GPA Majored in Insurance and Actuarial science Elected departmental President for student affair in 2014.
2006-09 - 2009-05	West African Examination Council Certificate: Arts

Additional Information

GitHub Profile: https://www.github.com/Tenica

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chika-

College Of The Immaculate Conception - Amaigbo

onyema-164114201

Lane, Uwani, Enugu State

Portfolio: https://www.chikaonyema.com

Interests

Reading

Coding and learning